Guide to the World War I Pamphlet Collection 1901-1944 (bulk 1914-1919)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Great Britain - Military: Campaigns / Battles (in Danish, Dutch and English), 1917-1919; Maude, Frederick Stanley. The London gazette for 10de Juli 1917 indeholdende Generalløitnant F.S. Maude's rapport til det engelske krigsministerium om den Mesopotamske ekspeditionsarme's operationer i tiden 28de august 1916 til 31te mars 1917. London: Darling & Son, 1917.; Maude, Frederick Stanley. Bericht van Luitenant-Generaal Sir Stanley Maude, Opperbevelhebber van het Britsch Leger in Mesopotamië. 20 aug., 1916-31 maart, 1917. London: Harrison and Sons, 1917.; Diary of the War. London: Daily News Book Dept., 1919.; Transcaucasia and the Caspian. The Globe, 1918. (Box-folder 24/6)
- Great Britain - Military: Pensions and Allowances (in English), 1914-1919; Separation Allowances for Soldiers, Sailors, and Airmen. London: Sir Joseph Causon & Sons, Ltd., 1918.; Separation Allowance Increased Rates for Wives and Children of Soldiers. S.l: S. B. Ltd., 1914.; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee Publications. Separation Allowance for dependants of unmarried soldiers (or widowers) during the War: No. 1 B. London: B. & F. Ltd., 1915.; War Pensions. S.O., F. Rd., 1919. (Box-folder 24/7)
- Great Britian - Military: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English), 1915-1917; The Treatment of Prisoners of War in England and Germany During the First Eight Months of the War. London: H.M. Stationery Office, 1915.; Great Britain, Ernest F. Spanton, and Jas Scott-Brown. Reports on the Treatment by the Germans of British Prisoners and Natives in German East Africa. London: H.M. Stationery Office, Harrison and Sons, Printers, 1917.; Further Correspondence with the United States Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of British Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in Germany. London: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1917. (Box-folder 24/8)
- Great Britian - Military: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in German), 1916; Ausschuss zur Untersuchung der Behandlung britischer Kriegsgefangener vonseiten des Feindes. Die Flecktyphusepidemie im Wittenberger Gefangenenlager: bericht des amtlichen Ausschusses zur Untersuchung der Behandlung britischer Kreigsgefangener vonseiten des Feindes. London: Darling, 1916. (Box-folder 24/9)
- Great Britain - Military: Recruitment (in English), 1914-1915 and undated; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee. Manifesto to the trade unionists of the country: No. 3. London: J.J. K. & Co., Ltd., 1914.; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee. Who said 'enough'? London: J.J. Keliher & Co., Ltd., 1914.; Kitchener, Horatio Herbert, Lord. Young men, your country needs you!: Parliamentary Recruiting Committee Publications, No. 17. London: Hazell, Watson & Viney, Ld., 1914.; Great Britain. To Welshmen. [Call to enlistment]. London: Hazell, Watson & Viney, Ltd, 1914.; Great Britain. Belgium: Belgium's Fight for Freedom. London: Parliamentary Recruiting Committee, 1914.; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee. The United Call to Arms. London: Harrison & Sons, 1914.; A Just Cause to a Successful End. The Rally of Our United Empire. London: Parliamentary Recruiting Committee, 1914.; Recruiting: list of commands, military districts and regimental areas. (Parliamentary Recruiting Committee Publications, No 4). 1914.; More Men Are Wanted for His Majesty's Army. [London]: Published by the Parliamentary Recruiting Committee, 1915.; Parliamentary Recruiting Committee. To the Men of Great Britain: A Call to Arms. London: Hazell, Watson & Viney, Ld., (Box-folder 24/10)
- Great Britain - Military: Service Histories and Pictorials (in English), 1916-1919 and undated; Welsh Regiments in the Great War: Stirring Deeds in France and Flanders. Cardiff: Western Mail, Ltd.,; A Souvenir for Visitors to the British Front. [With Plates and a Folding Map.]. Suffolk: R. Clay & Sons, Ltd., 1919.; The pictorial history of the war. London: W. H. Smith & Son, 1916. (Box-folder 24/11)
- Great Britain - Military: Warfare (in English), 1916-1918 and undated; Swinton, E. D. The "Tanks": (by Request, and with Permission). New York: George H. Doran Company, 1918.; Anderson, Jane, and Gordon Bruce. Flying, Submarining and Mine Sweeping. London: Sir J. Causton, 1916.; Anderson, R. Wherry. The Romance of Air-Fighting. New York: George H. Doran Company,; Air Ministry. Royal Air Force w/t Apparatus. Transmitter, Type 52b. 1918. (Box-folder 24/12)
- Great Britain - Military: Warfare, Naval (in Danish), 1916-1917 and undated; Masterman, Charles F. G. Flaadens Triumf. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode, 1916.; Carson, Edward Henry Carson. Forsvarskrigen mod de tyske undervandsbaade. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode, 1917.; Newbolt, Sir Henry. Under Vandskrigens Historie: En Kort Skildring. n.d. (Box-folder 24/13)
- Great Britain - Military: Warfare, Naval (in English), 1915-1918; Hurd, Archibald. Submarines and Zeppelins in Warfare and Outrage. London: Sir J. Causton & Sons, Limited, 1916.; Hurd, Archibald. If There Were No Navies! London: J. Truscott, 1916.; Newbolt, Henry J. S. A Note on the History of Submarine War. London: Longmans, Green & co, 1918.; Corbett, Julian S. The Spectre of Navalism. London: Thomas Nelson, 1915. (2 copies); Correspondence with the German Government Regarding the Alleged Misuse of British Hospital Ships. London: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1917. (Box-folder 25/1)
- Great Britain - Military: Warfare, Naval (in French), 1918; Bridge, Cyprian, and E. F. Fournier. Ce que le monde doit à la Marine britannique. Londres: Richard Clay, 1918. (Box-folder 25/2)
- Great Britain - Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in Danish and Dutch), 1915-1917; Asquith, H. H. Krigen. Dens anledning og budskab. London: Harrison and Sons, 1915.; Smuts, J. C. Het Britsche Gemeenebest van Naties. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (Box-folder 25/3)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), undated; National Unionist Association. The Government Record of War and Peace. Good, Ltd.,; A War of Liberation. New York: George H. Doran Company, (2 copies) (Box-folder 25/4)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), 1914; Cook, Edward Tyas. Why Britain Is at War, The Causes and the Issues, Set Out, in Brief Form, from the Diplomatic Correspondence and Speeches of Ministers. London: Macmillan, 1914.; Lloyd George, David. "Through Terror to Triumph!" A Speech Delivered...at the Queen's Hall, London, on September 19th, 1914. London: The Liberal Publication Department, 1914.; Asquith, H. H. The War, Its Causes and Its Message. London: Methuen & Co. Ltd, 1914.; A Reply to "Scaremongerings" and an Open Letter to Lord Northcliffe. London: The Daily News, Ltd., 1914. (Box-folder 25/5)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), 1915-1916; Masterman, Charles F. G. After Twelve Months of War. London: Darling, 1915.; Mills, J. Saxon. The Gathering of the Clans: How the British Dominions and Dependencies Have Helped in the War. London: T.F. Unwin, 1916. (Box-folder 25/6)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), 1917; Muir, Ramsay. The Character of the British Empire. London: Constable and Company Limited, 1917.; Why the War Must Go On. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917.; Smuts, J. C. The British Commonwealth of Nations. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917.; The Sunrise Annual, Ninth Issue. Warrington: The "Sunrise" Publishing Co., 1917. (Box-folder 25/7)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), 1918-1919; Smuts, Jan Christiaan. General Smuts's Message to South Wales: Speech Delivered at Tonypandy, Rhondda, on October 29, 1917. New York, N.Y.: George H. Doran Company, 1918.; Lloyd George, David. British War Aims. New York: George H. Doran company, 1918.; National Safety Movement. Why The Political Bulletin Is Issued. Ed. Dacre Fox. No. 1. The Political Bulletin: London, 1919. Print. (Box-folder 25/8)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda (in English), 1916-1918; The British Empire at War: The Men of the Empire; Their Homes and Their Battlefields. London: Robert and Leete, Ltd., 1916.; The War of Munitions: How Great Britain Has Mobilised Her Industries. London: Robert and Leete, Ltd., 1916. (2 copies); German Colonial Possessions Surrendered to the Allies Since August, 1914. London: Johnson, Riddle & Co., ca. 1916. (2 copies); A Reminder. London: R. Clay and Sons, Ltd., ca. 1918.; A Reminder from France. ca. 1918.; The World's Verdict on Germany. London: Wyman & Sons, Ltd., ca. 1916. (Box-folder OS 46)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda: Against the Catholic Church (in English), 1918; Bottomley, Horatio. John Bull and the Pope: The man who is delaying Peace. London: 1918. (2 copies); Stutfield, Hugh E. M. The Roman Church and the Entente. London: World's Evangelical Allaince, 1918.; Porcelli. The Pope and the War. London: Protestant Truth Society, 1918. (Box-folder 25/9)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in Danish and Dutch), 1917; Great Britain, and David Lloyd George. Fredsforslag og de allieredes standpunkt. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode, 1917.; Lloyd, George D. Vredes-voorstellen En De Houding Der Gealliëerden. London: Harrison and Sons, 1917. (Box-folder 25/10)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1914-1916 and undated; Blatchford, Robert. Germany and England. London: Associated Newspapers,; Begbie, Harold. Negotiate Now? A Business Man's Answer. An Interview with Lord Leverhulme. London: Smith,; Low, A. Maurice. Great Britain and the War. Washington, D.C.: Columbian printing co., inc, 1914.; Curzon, George Nathaniel. Germany's Move and Britain's Answer. London: Hayman, Christy & Lilly, 1916. (Box-folder 25/11)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1917; Prothero, G. W. A Lasting Peace: A Conversation between X. (a Neutral) and Y. (an Englishman). London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (2 copies); Robertson, J. M. The German Idea of Peace Terms. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1917.; Gosling, Harry. Peace: How to Get and Keep It. New York, N.Y.: G.H. Doran Co, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 25/12)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1917; Archer, William. The Villain of the World-Tragedy A Letter to Professor Ulrich V. Wilamowitz Möllendorf. London: T.F. Unwin, ltd, 1917.; Robertson, John M. Britain Versus Germany an Open Letter to Prof. Eduard Meyer of the University of Berlin. London: T. Fischer Unwin, 1917. (Box-folder 25/13)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1917-1918; French, John Denton Pinkstone, and Edward Price Bell. The Germans and the Small Nations: An Interview with Lord French. London: J.J. Keliher & Co, 1917.; Gibbs, Philip. The Germans on the Somme. London: Darling & Son, Ltd, 1917.; Robertson, J. M. German Truth and a Matter of Fact. London: T.F. Unwin, 1917.; Bevan, Edwyn Robert. Germany's Future with a Good Peace and a Bad Peace: A Translation and Reproduction of the German Brochure "Deutschlands Zukunft Bei Einem Guten Und Einem Schlechten Frieden." Containing All the Original Maps and Diagrams in Colours. London: Darling & Son, 1918. (this book was actually written from Germany's perspective and published in Germany; however, the book was reprinted in England as an example of German propaganda); Blatchford, Robert. Can We Win? London: W.H. Smith & Son, 1918. (Box-folder 25/14)
- Great Britian - Patriotic Propaganda: Against Germany (in French and Italian), 1917; French, John Denton Pinkstone, and Edward Price Bell. Les Allemands et les petites Nations. London: J.J. Keliher & Co, 1917.; "The Month.". Un Nuovo KulturKampf? Roma: Failli, 1917. (Box 25/15)
- Great Britain - Patriotic Propaganda: Cartoons (in English), 1914; The Daily Graphic. "The daily Graphic" special war cartoons. London: Baines, 1914. (Box-folder 25/16)
- Great Britain - Pro-German Propaganda (in English), 1915; Schrader, Frederick Franklin. England on the Witness Stand; The Anglo-German Case Tried by a Jury of Englishmen. New York: The Fatherland, 1915. (Box-folder 25/17)
- Great Britain - Public Opinions/Rights of Expression (in Danish), 1916; Murray, Gilbert. Etiske problemer fremkaldt af krigen: foredrag. London: Eyre & Spottiswoode, 1916. (Box-folder 25/18)
- Great Britain - Public Opinions/Rights of Expression (in English), 1915-1922 and undated; Graham, John W. War and the Survival of the Fittest. Bannisdale, Malton: E. E. Taylor,; Graham, John W. Evolution and Conquest. Bannisdale, Malton: E. E. Taylor,; Angell, Norman. Shall This War End German Militarism? London: Union of Democratic Control, 1915.; Russell, Bertrand. War, the Offspring of Fear. London: Union of Democratic Control,; Ponsonby, Arthur. Parliament and foreign policy. London: The Union of democratic control,; Asquith, Herbert Henry, Winston Spencer Churchill, and Edward Grey of Fallodon. The National Policy as set forth by Mr. [Herbert Henry] Asquith, Sir Edward Grey, Mr. Churchill [u.a.]. London: Union of Democr. Control, 1915.; The Union of Democratic Control. The International Industry of War. London:; Union of Democratic Control. Why We Should State Terms of Settlement. London: Union of Democratic Control,; Union of Democratic Control. Towards an International Understanding: Being the Opinions of Some Allied & Neutral Writers. London:; Swanwick, Helena M. Women and War. London: 1915.; Morel, E D. The Poison That Destroys: "the Case for a National Inquiry into the Causes of the War and the Disaster of the Peacc [sic]". London: Independent labour party, 1922. (Box-folder 25/19)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in Dutch and English), 1917-1918; The Men Who Tidy Up: By One Who has Served in a British Labour Battalion. London: T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd., 1917.; Forsyth, P.T. The Roots of a World Commonwealth. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1918; Forsyth, P. T. De Grondslagen van Een Wereld Statenbond. London: The British Evangelical Information Committee, 1918. (Box-folder 25/20)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1930; Our Empire: Unity and Development of the British Commonwealth, Vol. V. London: Hon. Secretary of the British Empire Service Leaugue, 1930. (Box-folder 26/1)
- Great Britain - Religious Propaganda (in Dutch and English), 1915-1917; Selbie, W B. Christelijk Nationalisme. Brieven in oorlogstijd Evangelical Information Committee, Nr. 2. Londen: Evangelical Information Committee, 1917.; Sanday, W. Wanneer De Oorlog Zal Kunnen Eindigen. Brieven in Oorlogstijd Evangelical Information Committee, nr. 1. Londen: Evangelical Information Committee, 1917.; Gwatkin, Henry Melvill. Britain's Case against Germany: A Letter to a Neutral. London: T.F. Unwin, 1917.; Selbie, W B. Christian Nationalism. Evangelical Information Committee, No. 2. London: Evangelical Information Committee, 1917.; Tracts for the Times. London: Bernard Quaritch, 1915. (Box-folder 26/2)
- Great Britain - War Memorials / Dedications (in English), 1917; Great Britain. Parliament's Vote of Thanks to the Forces: Speeches Delivered in the Houses of Parliament, Westminster, on October 29, 1917. London: H.M. Stationery Off, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 26/3)
- Great Britain - War Memorials / Dedications (in English), 1918-1919; St. Paul's Cathedral, June 13th, 1919. Memorial Service for the Royal Navy. London: R. E. Thomas & Co., 1919.; Kenyon, Frederic G. War Graves: How the Cemeteries Abroad Will Be Designed. London: H.M.S.O., 1918.; Greeting to Peace. Mr. Killon will take the chair, 1:15 p.m. Mitchell Memorial Hall. Manchester: 1918. (program for a church service or dedication); St. Paul's Cathedral. Memorial Service for those connected with British Banks who have fallen in the Great War, 1914-1918. R.E. Thomas & Co., 1919. (Box-folder 26/4)
- Great Britain - War Memorials / Dedications: Soldiers' Lists (in English), 1919 and undated; St. Paul's Cathedral, Wednesday, February 5th, 1919: In Memory of the Officers, Warrant Officers, Non-Commissioned Officers, and Men of the (Six Regiments of the) Brigade of Guards Who Have Died in the Service of Their Country During, the War, 1914-1918. 1919.; Choral Commemoration of the Heroic Deeds of the Frist Seven Division, Mons to Ypres, 1914. Kensington: S. Sidders & Son, (Box-folder 26/5)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort: Education / Rehabilitation (in English), 1914-1919 and undated; Professional Classes War Relief Council, London. [Handbook of the] Professional Classes War Relief Council, 13 & 14 Prince's Gate, S.W. London: The Council, 1914.; The Seal of Honour: National Scheme for Disabled Men. 1919.; To Disabled Sailors and Soldiers: A few Notes on the Advantages of Training for your Future Career. 1917.; Courses of Training for Discharged Sailors and Soldiers. Southampton. The University College of Southampton, n. d. (Box-folder 26/6)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort: Education / Rehabilitation (in English), 1920; National Scheme for Disabled Men. The King's National Roll. London: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1920. (Box-folder 26/7)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English), 1916; International Committee of the Red Cross, and Great Britain. Reprisals against Prisoners of War Correspondence between The International Red Cross Committee and the British Government. London: J. Causton & Sons, 1916.; Great Britain, Evelyn Mountstuart Grant Duff, and Heron Charles Goodhart. The Reception of Wounded Prisoner Soldiers of Great Britain in Switzerland. London: J. Truscott, 1916. (Box-folder 26/8)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English), 1917-1918; The Ruhleben Prisoners' Release Committee. The Ruhleben Prisoners: The Case for Their Release. London: 1917.; The Ruhleben Prisoners' Release Committee. The Ruhleben Prisoners: A Reasoned Plea for Immediate Release. Pamphlet No. 2. London: 1917.; The Ruhleben Prisoners' Release Committee. The Ruhleben Prisoners: The Government Attitude. Pamphlet No. 3. London: 1917.; The Ruhleben Prisoners' Release Committee. The Ruhleben Prisoners: Some Recent Parliamentary References. Pamphlet No. 4. London: 1917.; The Ruhleben Prisoners' Release Committee. The Ruhleben Prisoners: Imperative Necessity for Early Release. Pamphlet No. 5. London: 1918. (Box-folder 26/9)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort: Prisoners of War (POWs) (in English), 1918-1919; To Make Men Traitors Germany's Attempts to Seduce Her Prisoners-of-War. London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1918.; Central Prisoners of War Committee. Summary of Regulations and Directions Governing the Despatch of Parcels to Non-Commissioned Officers and Men who are Prisoners of War. London: 1918.; Ruhleben Exhitibion Central Hall, Westminster Jaunary 14th to February 8th, 1919: Catalogue of Exhibits. Westminster: The Abbey Press, 1919. (Box-folder 26/10)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort:Women's Volunteer Reserve (in English), 1916-1918; Women's Reserve Ambulance, London. Women's Reserve Ambulance, "the Green Cross Society," (Attached to the National Motor Volunteers), (Attached to D Division Metropolitan Police for Air Raid Defence). London: Hazell, Watson & Viney Ld, 1916.; Women's Volunteer Reserve Magazine. [London]: [s. n.], 1918. (Box-folder 26/11)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort:Wounded / Crippled (in English), 1916-1917 and undated; Bennett, Arnold. Wounded.; Stanley, Arthur. Mercy-workers..of the war. London: Joseph Causton, 1916.; The War on Hospital Ships: From the Narratives of Eye-Witnesses. London: T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd, 1917.; Walton, Sydney. I Am Coming With a Light: The Knights of Darkness. London: St. Clements Press, Ltd., n. d.; Treves, Sir Frederick. The King George Hospital: A General View. Westminster: The Abbey Press, (Box-folder 26/12)
- Great Britain - War Relief Effort:Wounded / Crippled (in English), 1917; The Military Convalescent Hospital, Woodcote Park, Epsom. London: The Qualis Photo Co., 1917. (book of photographs) (Box-folder 26/13)
- Greece - Atrocities Alleged: Against Turkey (in English), 1919; Vasilakaki, Christo. Public Lecture on Turks and Greeks, at King's College, Strand, London, Friday January 24th 1919. London: George S. Vellonis, 1919.; Germanos. The Turkish Atrocities in the Black Sea Territories: Copy of Letter of His Grace Germanos, Lord Archbishop of Amassia and Samsoun. Manchester: Norbury, Natzio & Co. Ltd, 1919.; Short Account of the Turkish Persecutions and Atrocities Committed against the Greeks in Turkey. London: London Committee of Unredeemed Greeks, 1919.; Eliou, L. Persecution and Extermination of the Communities of Macri and Livissi (1914-1918). Paris: Imprimerie Chaix, 1919. (Box-folder 26/14)
- Greece - Atrocities Alleged: Against Turkey (in French), 1918-1923; Athanasaki, Jean. Le Traitement Des Prisonniers Grecs En Turquie. Paris: Soc. génér. d'impr. et d'édit, 1923.; Les Persécutions Anti-Helléniques En Turquie Depuis Le Début De La Guerre Européenne: D'après Les Rapports Officiels Des Agents Diplomatiques Et Consulaires. Paris: Grasset, 1918.; Atrocités grecques à Eski-Chéhir. Relation d'un témoin oculaire de la débâcle des armées helléniques. Constantinople: Soc. an. de papéterie et d'imprimerie--Fratelli-Haim, 1922. (Box-folder 26/15)
- Greece - Education (in Greek), 1858; Professor Soustos. Ceremonial Address of the Political Economy. Athens?: Otto University, 1858. (Pamphlet written entirely in Greek characters; An address delivered on May 20, 1858, King Otto's birthday. This was also the day his University was founded. Otto, a Bavarian, was the first king of post-Turkish Greece.) (Box-folder 26/16)
- Greece - Military: Correspondence (in English and French), 1913; Extracts of some letters found in the mail of the 19th Regt. of the Greek 7th Division, seized by the Bulgarians in the region of Razlog. 1913. 1913.; Nouvelle série de lettres écrites à Mehomia, Nevroscope et d'autres localités du Razlog. 1913.; Extraits fac-similés de certaines lettres trouvées dans le courrier du 19ème régiment de la VIIème division grecque, saisi par les troupes bulgares dans la région de Razlog. 1913. Sofia: Impr. de la Cour Royale, 1913. (Box-folder 27/1)
- Greece - Military: Macedonia (in French), 1918-1919; Colonel M. L'Armée hellénique en Macédoine. Paris: L. Pochy, 1918.; Darvingoff, Petre. Histoire de la Legion Macedono-Andrinopolitaine: Premier Volume, la Vie et les Operations de la Legion dans la Guerre Contra le Turquie. Sofia: Imprimerie de l'Etat, 1919. (Box-folder 27/2)
- Greece - War News (in French), 1918; Bulletin d'informations hellénique. Paris: Imprimerie centrale de la Bourse, 1918. (several different issues from Nov. to Dec. 1918.; extremely fragile) (Box OS 43)
- Holland - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in Dutch, English and French), 1918; Hillis, Newell Dwight. Moord van de Laagste Aard. London: the field & Queen, 1918.; General Dutch League. The Campaign against Holland. Dordrecht: Algemeen Nederlandsch Verbond, 1918.; Algemeen Nederlandsch Verbond. La campagne contre la Hollande. Dordrecht: Algemeen Nederlandsch verbond, 1918. (Box-folder 27/3)
- Holland - Foreign Politics (in Dutch), 1915; Droogstoppel, Janus, and Jozef Buerbaum. De Duitsche strooptochten in Belgie: beschouwingen. Amsterdam: Boek- en chromodrukkerij, 1915. (This is a serial publication ranging from 4, 5, 7, 8) (Box-folder 27/4)
- Holland - Foreign Politics (in Dutch), 1915; Droogstoppel, Janus, and Jozef Buerbaum. De Duitsche strooptochten in Belgie: beschouwingen. Amsterdam: Boek- en chromodrukkerij, 1915. (This is a serial publication ranging from 9-13, 15, 18) (Box-folder 27/5)